BEREKET GIRMA

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

(702) 931-4006 | bereketgirma97@gmail.com | https://github.com/bereket-girma | https://bereketgirma.netlify.app https://www.linkedin.com/in/bereket-girma-82a87a1b1/

PROFILE

I am a versatile developer who specializes in JavaScript, React.js/Redux, Node.js, and Express to build web applications. Proven ability to complete projects to the highest standards within agreed deadlines. Problem-solver, disciplined, and highly motivated individual with a great attitude.

SKILLS

Proficient: JavaScript | React | Redux | REST API | Node.js | Express | HTML5 | CSS3 | Git | Github | SQL |

PostgreSQL | JSON

Exposure: socket.io | ¡Query | Bootstrap | SASS

EDUCATION

PunchCode August 2020 - November 2020

- -PunchCode is a full-time, immersive class that over 12-weeks will cover a career-focused curriculum that provides students with the foundation of being a Jr. Full-Stack Software Engineer.
- -Adequately acquired 500+ hours with technical and professional training and 700 hours work on coding
- -Acquired a strong familiarity with Git Version Control by contributing to group projects working closely with classmates
- -Became fluent with Scrum framework and working in an Agile methodology during the creation of Jellow App and Vegas Land
- -Received a certification of completion at the end of the intense cohort

College of Southern Nevada General Education

January 2020 - July 2020

-obtained 24 credit units towards Associate degree

Fuguay-Varina High School

-Obtained High School diploma

PROJECTS

Vegas Land

A curated website that promotes and highlights downtown and local businesses.

- -used React.js and Express.js to build the front and back end of the user interface
- -used postgreSQL to create a database for the entire project
- -used Google API to display active happy hours in the downtown area

Jellow App

Recreated Trello, a web-based Kanban-style list-making application.

EMPLOYMENT

Medical Transcriptionist | Home Health Nurses | Las Vegas

- -Managed and converted voice recordings that physicians & other healthcare workers make into written reports
- -Review transcription documents for QA to spot and correct any errors that could impact patient care and medical liability

-Isolate mistakes or inconsistencies in a medical report and correct the information.

Accounting Assistant | Higuchi Group | Las Vegas

- -Processed invoices and managed vendor accounts
- -Prepared company accounts and tax returns for audit
- -Prepared weekly report and budget
- -Monitored and recorded company expenses

November 2018 - January 2020

January 2018 - September 2018